tigerair.com 2019-05-15

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

 **Last Updated: 20 July 2018**

This is the Scoot Tigerair Pte. Ltd. (“Scoot”, “we”, “our”) Privacy Policy. 

We are a corporation registered in the Republic of Singapore with company number 200312665W and a registered office at 25 Airline Road, Airline House, Singapore 819829. For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and other applicable data protection laws, we are the data controller. Our data protection officer can be contacted at [privacy@flyscoot.com](mailto:privacy@flyscoot.com). Our representative in the European Union (“EU”) is our UK establishment, Singapore Airlines UK, a branch registered at Building 11, Chiswick Park, 566 Chiswick High Road, London W4 5YS, United Kingdom.

Scoot collects, uses and discloses Customer Data (as defined below) in order to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient and customised experience with Scoot. The collection, use and disclosure of Customer Data enables Scoot to provide services and products that are most likely to meet your needs and requirements. This Privacy Policy outlines Scoot’s policy and responsibility in relation to the collection, use and disclosure of Customer Data.

By continuing to use Scoot’s services, you signify that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy. 

### SUMMARY

#### What information do we collect about you?

We collect information when you purchase flights or other products on our website or mobile application, such as your contact details, credit card information, and travel information. We also collect information about your preferences from your interactions with our in-flight and ground-based staff, and from specific requests you make. In addition, we collect device and technical information from you when you use our website or mobile application. 

More Information

#### How will we use the information about you?

We use your information to fulfil our contract of carriage with you, and to administer your membership with our Scoot Insider programme. We also use your information to maintain our website and mobile application, and to tailor our products and services to your preferences to provide the best service possible. In addition, we use your information to market our products and services to you, and those of our group companies, partners and agents (with your consent where required by applicable law). 

More Information

#### Who do we share your information with?

We share your data with our third party service providers to the extent necessary for them to provide their services such as payment processors, ground-operating personnel, travel-related service partners and in-flight entertainment. We use these third parties services solely to process or store your information for the purposes described in this policy. We also share your information with our code share partners, interline partners, strategic alliance partners, other carriers who help us provide our services, related group companies and our overseas stations and offices and with government bodies as required by law. 

More Information

#### Where do we process your information?

Our servers are located in Singapore, Australia and the United Kingdom. We transfer your information to airports, and ground staff in destinations that you are flying to and where we operate. Our staff are located in our foreign branch or representative offices around the world such as Australia, China, Malaysia, the Philippines, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Greece, India, the United States of America, Thailand, Bangladesh, Indonesia, Taiwan and Saudi Arabia. 

More Information

#### How long do we keep hold of your information?

We retain your information for as long as it is necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it was collected, the legal or business purposes of Scoot, or as required by relevant laws. We will usually keep your Customer Data for up to 7 years to ensure that any contractual disputes can be addressed. For EU and Swiss residents, we will endeavour to delete data within 30 days of a request for deletion or contact you if it will take longer. 

More Information

#### How can I exercise my rights over my information?

You may have rights to access and correct, receive a copy of, or delete, your data or restrict or object to our processing of, your data. 

More information if you are not residing in the EU or Switzerland

More information if you are residing in the EU or Switzerland

### Dispute Resolution

If you have any concerns or complaints, please contact us **here** .

#### How will we notify you of changes?

Scoot will amend this Privacy Policy from time to time and the updated versions will be posted on Scoot’s Website and date stamped so that you are aware of when the Privacy Policy was last updated. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will provide notice including by banner on our website.

More Information

### Part A: General Customer Data privacy policy statement

#### 1\. The types of Customer Data we collect

The types of Customer Data that Scoot collects depends on the circumstances of collection and on the nature of the service requested or transaction undertaken. 

There are two broad categories of Customer Data that Scoot collects:

  * 1) Personal Data. The data we collect includes but is not limited to: 
    1. personal information that can be used to identify an individual, such as name, gender, date of birth, passport or other personal identification numbers;
    2. contact information, such as address, phone number, email address;
    3. payment information, such as credit or debit card information, including the name of cardholder, card number, billing address and expiry date;
    4. travel information, such as ticket numbers, destinations, flight information; 
    5. information on your other purchases made through Scoot, such as tracking your purchases of selectable seats, check-in baggage, seat upgrades, and purchases of travel-related services like travel insurance and WiFi data through our website;
    6. your customer preferences, such as dietary, seating, places that you would like to visit or other service preferences;
    7. information about your interactions with our ground and call centre staff, such as the details of any complaint cases, incidences of lost baggage, call details, and other information relevant to assist our ground or call centre staff to service you;
    8. health information, such as doctors’ notes and requests related to medical conditions;   
and
    9. business contact information, such as the contact details of the employees of our vendors and corporate customers, as well as the contact details collected by our ultimate holding company (“Singapore Airlines Limited”) and its subsidiaries (the “SIA group”).
  * 2) Technical Data. As further explained in Part B, this includes device and technical information you give us when using our website or mobile application (“Website”).

For purposes of this policy statement, Customer Data means Personal Data and Technical Data.

We also use Customer Data to derive Statistical Data, such as the number of passengers. This is processed and stored purely for analytical purposes, and is entirely anonymous. This information will not be stored to your customer record, and will only be aggregated for statistical analysis so that we can better understand Scoot's customer profile and improve Scoot's service offering.

#### Special categories of information or “sensitive personal data” 

Certain categories of Customer Data, such as information about your race, ethnicity, religion or health, are considered special categories of information, or “sensitive personal data” under the GDPR. 

Generally, we try to limit the circumstances where we collect your sensitive personal data. However, this can occasionally occur because you have made certain requests in connection with your travel arrangements that reveal or suggest something about you that could be considered “sensitive personal data”, or if you otherwise choose to provide such information to us (or a third party such as the travel agent through which you made your booking).

For example:

  * if you request a particular type of meal, e.g. halal or kosher meals, this may imply or suggest that you are a member of a particular religion; or
  * if you request specific medical assistance from us and/or an airport operator, e.g. the provision of a wheelchair, this may reveal that you have a particular medical condition. 

#### How we collect data from you 

Scoot collects Customer Data, either directly from you or from your authorised representatives (i.e. persons whom you have authorised and/or persons who have been validly identified as being your authorised representative (e.g. your organisation’s corporate travel manager) pursuant to our then-current security procedures. 

Scoot also collects Customer Data from third parties which are located in various countries. This includes, but is not limited to, travel agents, our service providers, other airlines including those in the SIA group, to facilitate travel on code share or multi-airline flights, through our Website, mobile services, your interactions with us on our social media websites and other channels including our airport operations. 

Where you make reservations on behalf of another person, you undertake and will ensure that the individual whose Customer Data is supplied to Scoot has authorised the disclosure, is informed of and agrees to the provisions of this Privacy Policy. 

#### 2\. Is the provision of Customer Data required? 

The collection of the following types of Customer Data is mandatory to enable Scoot to fulfil our contract of carriage with you. These types of Customer Data are marked as mandatory on our booking form. If you do not provide this information, you will not be able to book flights on our airlines and we will not be able to provide you with our services and/or products required.

  * Passenger details, e.g title, first/given name, last/family name, date of birth, whether you are residing in the EU or Switzerland.. 
  * Contact details, e.g. email address, mobile phone number, home number or business number, title, first name, last name. 
  * Payment details, e.g. the name on the credit or debit card, the number, expiry date and security code on the credit or debit card, and billing address. 

Additional information may be mandatory if you are flying to a specific country, or if you are flying on behalf of a business registered in a specific country, e.g. your gender, nationality, passport number, the country of issue of your passport, the name, GST registration number and address of the business you are flying on behalf of, and your business email address and phone number. For example, if you are flying a route that touches Honolulu, your country of birth, passport number, the country of issue of your passport and your passport expiry date is required. If you have purchased travel insurance through our web portals and, are travelling from Taiwan, your Taiwan ID is required, travelling from China, your passport ID is required. These mandatory fields will be clear when you make a booking. 

The collection of the following types of Customer Data is mandatory to enable Scoot to administer your membership with our Scoot Insider programme: (i) title; (ii) last/family name; (iii) first name; (iv) date of birth; (iv) email address; (v) mobile phone number; and (vi) location; and (ix) whether you are residing in the EU or Switzerland. 

These types of Customer Data are marked as mandatory on our sign up form. If you do not provide this information, you will not be able to benefit from the utility, promotions and engagement exclusive to members holding a Scoot Insider profile. 

The failure to supply the following types of Customer Data will result in (i) Scoot being unable to update you on our latest products and/or launches; and/or (ii) your inability to enter or participate in contests, promotions or redemption activities organised by Scoot: Contact Information e.g. name, email address, telephone number (to verify your country of residence), and address (if the prize need to be mailed).

#### 3\. How we use your Customer Data 

If you are residing in the EU or Switzerland, we are required to disclose the legal basis for processing your data under the GDPR and the Swiss Data Protection Act. We will use the Customer Data in the following ways:

In accordance with our contract with you, we will use the Customer Data to:

  * process and assist you with any transactions related to your booking (e.g., making a booking, providing services related to the booking (e.g., seat selection and upgrades, meal preferences, WiFi data and insurance purchased through our website, etc), and fulfilling such booking);
  * notify you about changes to our service;
  * facilitate airport, internet check-in and self check-in;
  * provide airport services such as processing information relating to connecting flights, arrangements at airports, and customs and immigration facilities;
  * provide baggage related services such as processing of any baggage related queries, including mishandled or missing baggage claims;
  * provide in-flight catering and other services (e.g. to provide you with a personalised inflight experience);
  * if you are a Scoot Insider member: 
    * to maintain your Scoot Insider account; and
    * facilitate membership-related transactions and services.

As it is in our legitimate interests to be responsive to you, to provide customised services and marketing and to ensure the proper functioning of our products, services and organisation, we will use your Customer Data to:

  * respond to your enquiries, requests or feedback;
  * enforce our terms, conditions and policies; 
  * communicate with you;
  * improve the Website and to ensure content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your device;
  * administer the Website and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes; 
  * send you surveys by post or email. You can opt-out of receiving these surveys at any time by contacting us, via our Website or our social media pages, or by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link on an email from us;
  * send you service emails, such as reminders when you have not checked out your purchases on our Website. You can opt-out of receiving service emails at any time by contacting us, via our Website or social media pages, or by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link on an email from us;
  * allow you to participate in interactive features of the Website, when you choose to do so;
  * customise our products and services to you, including by responding to and catering for your customer preferences;
  * personalise the content you see on our Website;
  * keep the Website safe and secure; 
  * aggregate Customer Data into anonymised statistical data (such as number of passengers flown on a particular journey), which we will use for statistical analysis so that we can better understand Scoot's customer profile and improve Scoot's service offering; 
  * to customise our marketing e.g. send you targeted marketing on places you would like to visit, based on your responses to optional questions on our Website and your prior travels. If you are residing in the EU or Switzerland, you can object to this profiling and opt-out of receiving such targeted marketing. For more information on this right, click **here** ; 
  * send you marketing and promotional materials in relation to products and services offered by Scoot, Scoot’s subsidiaries and affiliated airlines and service partners, as well as Scoot’s appointed agents (provided we have your consent and/or have provided the opportunity to opt-out, in each case where required by applicable law); and 
  * In relation to our Scoot Insider programme: 
    * market and communicate to Scoot Insider members information on Scoot and Scoot Insider promotions, contests, events and lucky draws, including those conducted by Scoot Insider partners (with your consent where required by applicable laws); 
    * contact Scoot Insider members regarding product and customer related surveys and market research; 
    * respond to email and call enquiries from Scoot Insider members; and 
    * provide services to celebrate special occasions.
    * send Scoot Insider members Scoot Insider-related news and Scoot Insider e-statements and associated promotions and offers (with your consent where required by applicable laws).
  * if you are an employee of an entity with a contractual relationship with Scoot 
    * to contact you to perform our services, and in particular, to monitor and record calls for quality, training, analysis and other related purposes in order to pursue our legitimate interest to improve service delivery, 
    * enforce our terms and conditions against your employer; and
    * communicate with you about products, services, promotions, events and other news and information we think will be of interest to you. 
    * If you are residing in the EU or Switzerland, you can object to this profiling and opt-out of receiving such targeted marketing. For more information on this right, click **here**. 

With your consent where required by applicable laws, we will use your Customer Data to register you for a Scoot Insider Account. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us, via our Website or social media pages, or via the Scoot Insider portal on our Website.

#### 4\. Disclosure of your Customer Data

Scoot will share your Customer Data with selected third parties in the situations set out below: 

  * our travel and freight service providers or travel-related businesses and service providers (including ground personnel, security personnel, travel insurance providers, insurance providers and providers of WiFi, if you purchase elect to use such services), partner airlines, airport management, airport operators;
  * our code share partners, interline partners and strategic alliance partners so that they can fulfil their contract of carriage for the flights you booked through Scoot and, where applicable, provide you with the relevant benefits of their frequent flier programme. Where Customer Data is shared with such partners, the Customer Data will be used by that partner in accordance their respective privacy policy;
  * advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others;
  * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of the Website.

Scoot will share your Customer Data with any member of our group, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries in order to better customise your preferences when you travel with Scoot, such as Singapore Airlines Limited (SIA), SilkAir (Singapore) Private Limited and Tradewinds Tours & Travel Private Limited. 

  * **For the purposes of our contract with you, i.e. to:**

(a) Fulfill bookings and facilitate flight transfers of passengers;   
(b) Manage passengers who travel on flights operated by our Singapore Airlines Limited and airlines in the SIA group and are both Scoot Insider and KrisFlyer members;   
(c) Manage passengers during flight disruptions and provide necessary assistance and services; 

  * **As it in our legitimate interests to be responsive to you, and to provide customised services and marketing, to:**

(d) Respond to complaints or compliments received by Scoot from passengers who are sharing their flight experience on flights operated by airlines in the SIA group;  
(e) Anticipating the servicing needs of passengers on flights in connection with (a)-(d) above;  
(f) Providing an enhanced customer experience and personalising offers to passengers;  
(g) Understand customers better through analytics and research (including marketing research) to support personalisation; and   
(h) Contact customers about Scoot Insider membership related updates and offers. 

  * To undertake targeted direct marketing and other forms of marketing or advertisement, provided we have consent of the recipient and/or have provided the opportunity to opt-out, in each case where required by applicable law.

Scoot will also use and disclose your Customer Data to persons who have been validly identified as being you or your authorised representative(s) pursuant to our then-current security procedures, for the purpose of the relevant transaction or enquiry. In particular, each of the passengers who are grouped under the same Passenger Name Record (“ **PNR** ”) number shall be deemed to be authorised representatives of each of the other passengers under the same PNR number, for the purposes of disclosure identified in this policy.

Scoot will disclose your Customer Data to law enforcement agencies, public or regulatory authorities, securities commissions or other organisations for security, customs and immigration purposes, if legally required to do so, or if we have a good faith belief that such use is reasonably necessary to:

  * comply with legal obligation, process or request;
  * enforce our terms and conditions and other agreements, including investigation of any potential violation thereof;
  * detect, prevent or otherwise address security, fraud or technical issues; or
  * protect the rights, property, health or safety of us, our users, a third party or the public as required or permitted by law (including exchanging Customer Data with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction).

For example, Scoot and other airlines are required by laws in the United States of America and other countries to provide border control agencies with access to your booking information or flight itinerary. Accordingly, relevant Customer Data (known as PNR or Advance Passenger Information (“API”)) will be disclosed to the appropriate customs and immigration authorities as required by law.

We will also disclose your Customer Data to third parties:

  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * if we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case Customer Data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets; or
  * to comply with legal obligations, processes or requests (such as disclosing Customer Data to executors in response to court orders).

In addition, Scoot may disclose Customer Data to our legal advisors for establishing, exercising or defending our legal rights, to our other professional advisors, or as otherwise authorised or required by law. Scoot also reserves the right to share Customer Data as is necessary to prevent a threat to the life, health or security of an individual or corporate entities such as Scoot. Further, Scoot will disclose Customer Data, as is necessary, to investigate suspected unlawful activities including but not limited to fraud, intellectual property infringement or privacy.

#### 5\. Transfer of information overseas

The Scoot Head Office is based in Singapore. Customer Data will be transmitted to data storage facilities where Scoot keeps its central records. Customer Data will be transferred to Scoot’s foreign branch and representative offices and appointed agents, including ground handling agents, sales agents and contact centre agents, in Singapore and around the world in connection with Scoot’s performance of the contract with you.

This means that Customer Data will be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside of your country and outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"), and in particular to Singapore, Australia and the United Kingdom where we have data centres. 

We will transfer Customer Data to airports and ground crew in destinations that you are flying to in and where we operate. The Customer Data is transferred outside the EEA and Switzerland on the basis that it is necessary for the performance of the contract of carriage between you and SIA. 

We will also transfer Customer Data to our code share, interline, and joint venture partners in strategic alliances in the Republic of Korea, the Philippines, Thailand, Japan Australia and Greece for the purposes of performing any contract of carriage. 

If you are residing in the EU and Switzerland, where we transfer Customer Data outside the EEA and Switzerland, this done either on the basis that it is necessary for the performance of the contract of carriage between you and Scoot, or that the transfer is subject to the European Commission’s model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries (i.e., the standard contractual clauses), pursuant to Decision 2004/915/EC and Decision 2010/87/EU as appropriate. 

The Customer Data will also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA and Switzerland who work for us, for one of our suppliers or one of our business partners. Such staff are engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services.

#### 6\. Non-EU and Non-Swiss Data Subject Rights

If you are not residing in the EU or Switzerland, you may have certain rights in relation to the Customer Data we hold about you, which we detail below.

##### Access.

You have the right to know whether we process Customer Data about you, and if we do, to access Customer Data we hold about you and certain information about how we use it and who we share it with. 

Where permitted by law, Scoot reserves the right to charge a reasonable administrative fee for this service. In exceptional circumstances, Scoot reserves the right to deny you access to your Customer Data and may provide an explanation as required by applicable laws. 

Exceptional circumstances include (to the extent allowable under applicable law) where:

  * An investigating authority or government institution objects to Scoot complying with a customer’s request,
  * The information may, in the exercise of Scoot’s reasonable discretion and/or assessment, affect the life or security of an individual, and
  * Data is collected in connection with an investigation of a breach of contract, suspicion of fraudulent activities or contravention of law.

##### Correction.

You have the right to correct any Customer Data held about you that is inaccurate. 

##### Exercise of Rights.

 _To exercise any of your rights, please use the following form:[ **Data Privacy Rights Form**](https://cdn.flyscoot.com/prod/docs/default-source/privacy-policy/personal_data_request.pdf?sfvrsn=8fa8d922_2) and submit it to [privacy@flyscoot.com](mailto:privacy@flyscoot.com)_. For Scoot Insider member members, you may correct any Customer Data by logging into your Scoot Insider account under the section titled “Profile” and “Preferences”. 

#### 7\. EU and Swiss Data Subject Rights

If you are residing in the EU or Switzerland, you may have certain rights in relation to the Customer Data we hold about you, which we detail below. Some of these only apply in certain circumstances as set out in more detail below. We also set out how to exercise those rights. 

These rights include: 

  * The right of access. More Information
  * The right of data portability. More Information
  * The right of rectification. More Information
  * The right of erasure. More Information
  * The right to restrict processing. More Information
  * The right to object. More Information

Please note that we will require you to provide us with proof of identity and address before responding to any requests to exercise your rights. We must respond to a request by you to exercise those rights without undue delay and at least within one month (although this may be extended by a further two months in certain circumstances). To exercise any of your rights, please use the following form: _[**Data Privacy Rights Form**](https://cdn.flyscoot.com/prod/docs/default-source/privacy-policy/personal_data_request.pdf?sfvrsn=8fa8d922_2) and submit it to [privacy@flyscoot.com](matilto:privacy@flyscoot.com)_. 

##### Complaints. 

In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how we process your Customer Data, please contact us and we will endeavour to deal with your request as soon as possible. This is without prejudice to your right to launch a claim with your data protection authority or follow the Dispute Process.

##### Access.

You have the right to know whether we process Customer Data about you, and if we do, to access Customer Data we hold about you and certain information about how we use it and who we share it with. 

If you require more than one copy of the Customer Data we hold about you, we may charge an administration fee.

We may not provide you with certain Customer Data if providing it would interfere with another’s rights (e.g. where providing the Customer Data we hold about you would reveal information about another person) or where another exemption applies.

##### Portability.

You have the right to receive a subset of the Customer Data we collect from you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and a right to request that we transfer such Customer Data to another party. 

The relevant subset of Customer Data is data that you provide us with your consent (please see **here** for the types of Customer Data we process on the basis of your consent, or for the purposes of performing our contract with you (please see **here** for the types of Customer Data we process on the basis of our contract with you. 

If you wish for us to transfer the Customer Data to another party, please ensure you detail that party and note that we can only do so where it is technically feasible. We are not responsible for the security of the Customer Data or its processing once received by the third party. We also may not provide you with certain Customer Data if providing it would interfere with another’s rights (e.g. where providing the Customer Data we hold about you would reveal information about another person).

##### Correction.

You have the right to correct any Customer Data held about you that is inaccurate. Please note that whilst we assess whether the Customer Data we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you may exercise your right to restrict our processing of the applicable data as described below. 

_To exercise any of your rights, please use the following form:[ **Data Privacy Rights Form**](https://cdn.flyscoot.com/prod/docs/default-source/privacy-policy/personal_data_request.pdf?sfvrsn=8fa8d922_2) and submit it to [privacy@flyscoot.com](mailto:privacy@flyscoot.com)._ For Scoot Insider member members, you may correct any Customer Data by logging into your Scoot Insider account under the section titled “Profile” and “Preferences”. 

##### Erasure. 

You may request that we erase the Customer Data we hold about you in the following circumstances:

  * you believe that it is no longer necessary for us to hold the Customer Data we hold about you;
  * we are processing the Customer Data we hold about you on the basis of your consent (please see **here** for the types of Customer Data we process on the basis of your consent ), and you wish to withdraw your consent and there is no other ground under which we can process the Customer Data;
  * we are processing the Customer Data we hold about you on the basis of our legitimate interest and you object to such processing (please see **here** for the types of Customer Data we process on that basis ). Please provide us with detail as to your reasoning so that we can assess whether there is an overriding interest for us to retain such Customer Data; 
  * you no longer wish us to use the Customer Data we hold about you in order to send you promotions, special offers, marketing and lucky draws; or 
  * you believe the Customer Data we hold about you is being unlawfully processed by us.

Also note that you may exercise your right to restrict our processing the Customer Data whilst we consider your request as described below.   
Please provide as much detail as possible on your reasons for the request to assist us in determining whether you have a valid basis for erasure. However, we may retain the Customer Data if there are valid grounds under law for us to do so (e.g., for the defence of legal claims or freedom of expression) but we will let you know if that is the case. Please note that after deleting the Customer Data, we may not be able to provide the same level of servicing to you as we will not be aware of your preferences.  
Where you have requested that we erase Customer Data that we have made public and there are grounds for erasure, we will use reasonable steps try to tell others that are displaying the Customer Data or providing links to the Customer Data to erase the Customer Data too.  
To exercise any of your rights, please use the following form: [**Data Privacy Rights Form**](https://cdn.flyscoot.com/prod/docs/default-source/privacy-policy/personal_data_request.pdf?sfvrsn=8fa8d922_2) and submit it to [privacy@flyscoot.com](mailto:privacy@flyscoot.com). For members, you can also erase your data by logging into your Scoot Insider account under the section titled “Profile” and “Preferences”. 

##### Restriction of Processing to Storage Only. 

You have a right to require us to stop processing the Customer Data we hold about you other than for storage purposes in certain circumstances. Please note, however, that if we stop processing the Customer Data, we may use it again if there are valid grounds under data protection law for us to do so (e.g. for the defence of legal claims or for another’s protection). 

You may request we stop processing and just store the Customer Data we hold about you where:

  * you believe the Customer Data is not accurate for the period it takes for us to verify whether the Customer Data is accurate;
  * we wish to erase the Customer Data as the processing we are doing is unlawful but you want us to retain the Customer Data but just store it instead;
  * we wish to erase the Customer Data as it is no longer necessary for our purposes but you require it to be stored for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or
  * you have objected to us processing Customer Data we hold about you on the basis of our legitimate interest and you wish us to stop processing the Customer Data whilst we determine whether there is an overriding interest in us retaining such Customer Data.

##### Objection. 

At any time you have the right to object to our processing of Customer Data about you in order to send you promotions, special offers, marketing messages, including where we build profiles for such purposes and we will stop processing the Customer Data for that purpose.   
You also have the right to object to our processing of Customer Data about you and we will consider your request in other circumstances as detailed below by using the following form: [**Data Privacy Rights Form**](https://cdn.flyscoot.com/prod/docs/default-source/privacy-policy/personal_data_request.pdf?sfvrsn=8fa8d922_2) and submitting it to [privacy@flyscoot.com](mailto:privacy@flyscoot.com) referencing: Data Subject Rights. 

You may object where: 

  * we are processing the Customer Data we hold about you (including where the processing is profiling) on the basis of our legitimate interest and you object to such processing [(please see **here** for the types of Customer Data we process on that basis . Please provide us with detail as to your reasoning so that we can assess whether there is a compelling overriding interest in us continuing to process such data or we need to process it in relation to legal claims. Also note that you may exercise your right to request that we stop processing the Customer Data whilst we make the assessment on an overriding interest by indicating this in our Data Privacy Rights form.

#### 8\. Retention

We will usually keep your Customer Data for a maximum of 7 years to ensure that any contractual disputes can be addressed. This includes standing requests which contain sensitive personal data about yourself, e.g. a standing request that you wish to receive a halal meal or a wheelchair at the airport. You can amend your standing request at any time to change your preferences in the future.

If you opt-out or withdraw your consent to marketing, we will remove you from our marketing database.

#### 9\. Accuracy

Scoot needs your assistance to ensure that your Customer Data is current, complete and accurate. As such, please inform Scoot of changes to your Customer Data by contacting Scoot and submitting your updated particulars to Scoot in writing (see Section 14). For Scoot Insider members, you may update your Customer Data at any time by logging into your Scoot Insider account under the section titled “Profile” and “Preferences”.

Scoot will also request Customer Data updates from you from time to time. As detailed above, your booking information or flight itinerary will be disclosed to the appropriate customs and immigration authorities as required by law. As such, it is important to ensure that the Customer Data contained in your booking information or flight itinerary is current, complete and accurate.

#### 10\. Security safeguards

Scoot takes the protection of your Customer Data seriously but, unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Customer Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your Customer Data transmitted through the Website; any transmission is at your own risk.

#### 11\. Links to other websites 

Scoot may, from time to time, provide you with links to other websites for your convenience and information. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. You access these websites at your own risk and Scoot is not responsible for these websites. Whilst Scoot will protect your Customer Data on Scoot Website, Scoot cannot control or be responsible for the policies of other sites we may link to, or the use of any Customer Data you may share with them. Please note that the Scoot Privacy Policy does not cover these other websites, and Scoot would recommend that you are apprised of their specific policies.

#### 12\. Minors

Scoot's Website is not directed at children under the age of 16 and Scoot cannot distinguish the age of persons who access and use its Website. If a minor (according to applicable laws) has provided Scoot with Customer Data without parental or guardian consent, the parent or guardian should contact Scoot (see Section 14) to remove the relevant Customer Data and unsubscribe the minor. If we become aware that Customer Data has been collected from a person under the age of 16 without parental or guardian consent, we will delete this Customer Data and, where that minor has an account, terminate the minor’s account. 

#### 13\. Updates to the privacy policy

Scoot will amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, and the updated versions will be posted on Scoot’s Website and date stamped so that you are aware of when the Privacy Policy was last updated. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will provide notice including by way of a banner on our website. Subject to applicable laws, the English version of this Privacy Policy will prevail over any version of this Privacy Policy in another language. 

### Cookies Policy 

#### 1\. Information Collected

In addition to Customer Data, when you visit our website or mobile application (“ **Website** ”), we collect technical information such as IP addresses or other unique identifiers, cookies, mobile carrier, time zone setting, operating system and platform, device ID and browser information. 

#### 2\. Cookies

Cookies are small files placed on your computer by websites that you visit or certain emails you open. 

By using the Scoot Website, you consent to Scoot’s use of cookies to collect and use your personal data in order to collect Website usage data, and improve your online experience. 

This can include information about the way you use the Website, your choice of internet browser, the type of device you are accessing it from, and where you are in the world. If you do not consent to Scoot’s use of cookies to collect and use your personal data, you may opt out of cookie use by following the instructions under the section “Accepting the use of cookies” below. 

#### Online behavioural advertising

Online behavioural advertising (also known as interest-based advertising) is a way of serving advertisements on the websites visited by you and making them more relevant to your interests. Shared interests are grouped together based upon previous web browsing activity in order for you to be served advertising which matches your shared interests. In this way, advertising can be made as relevant and useful as possible. Relevant ads can also be delivered based upon the website content you have just been viewing. This is known as ‘retargeting’. If you do not wish to be targeted for behavioural advertising, you may opt out of cookie use by following the instructions under the section “Accepting the use of cookies” below. Opting out does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the company or companies from which you opted out will no longer deliver adverts tailored to your web preferences and usage patterns, so you may see a greater number of adverts that are irrelevant to you and your preferences.

#### Accepting the use of cookies

You may refuse to accept cookies by altering the settings on your internet browser. If you choose not to allow the use of cookies, some areas of the Scoot Website may not be accessible or function properly.

Information about online behavioural advertising and deleting or controlling cookies is available at:

  * For EU customers: [ www.AboutCookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/)
  * For US customers: [www.NetworkAdvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/); [www.AboutAds.info](https://www.aboutads.info/)

If you delete your cookies, Scoot will no longer know that you have opted out of online behavioural advertising, recognise that you have agreed to Scoot’s Terms and Conditions, Privacy Policy and use of cookies, as well as remember your language and country selections. This means that banners from Scoot’s third-party websites will appear. Where necessary, you will be required to accept the use of cookies and provide all other cookie-related information again. 

#### Purposes of cookie collection and use

Scoot uses cookies on our Website for the following purposes:

  * Technical  
To enable the efficient working of the Scoot Website, including but not limited to:  
a) balancing Website traffic to ensure all users receive consistent and reliable service;  
b) limiting traffic to key parts of the Website in order to maintain performance levels; and  
c) storing the user’s acceptance of Scoot’s Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy.
  * Ease of use  
Cookies are used to make navigation easier for you, including but not limited to:  
a) remembering your language selection and country and presenting relevant content;  
b) keeping track of your KrisFlyer membership number when you have logged in; and  
c) providing the most relevant departure airport for your location when you are booking a flight.
  * Tracking  
Cookies are used to gather statistics on how you navigate and transact on our Website, including but not limited to:  
a) gathering feedback on your satisfaction through a survey; anda) gaining insight into how you navigate and transact on our Website so that improvements can be made to its usability.
  * Marketing  
Cookies are used to enable Scoot to present appropriate messages to you, including but not limited to:  
a) allowing our Website to serve up different versions of a page for marketing purposes;  
b) allowing third parties to display appropriate advertising and to track its effectiveness; and  
c) displaying of relevant messages, which offer a selection of products based on your viewing behaviour on our Website and other selected websites.

We also use web analytics services, such as Google Analytics. Google utilises the data collected to track and examine the use of [www.flyscoot.com](https://www.flyscoot.com/en/), to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected to contextualise and personalise the ads of its own advertising network. For more details, please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy.

For Google:

  * Google Analytics cookies across all websites, please visit Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on;
  * Other third party cookies relating to behavioural advertising, please go to [www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (in the EU); [www.AboutAds.info](https://www.aboutads.info/) (in the US)

#### Partnership with Adara and Sojern

Scoot partners with advertising networks, Adara (Adara.com) and Sojern (Sojern.com), to capture non-personally identifiable data from you through third-party cookies. This enables Adara and Sojern to display targeted and relevant messages from selected third-party websites, based on your viewing behaviour on the Scoot Website and other selected websites.

Your non-personally identifiable data is shared by Scoot with Adara and Sojern in the strictest confidence, for the unique purpose of serving more relevant advertising. Standards have been defined to ensure appropriate advertising is served, and all served advertisements offer the possibility for you to opt out of such selective advertising by Adara and Sojern. However, we have no control over the use of cookies by Adara and Sojern.

There are two ways for you to opt-out of cookie use:

For Adara
  * By visiting <https://adara.com/privacy-promise/opt-out> and clicking ‘Submit’; or
  * Through the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising, of which Adara is member. Each of these programmes provides an opt-out page where you can exercise control over members/’participants’ cookies from a central location.

For Sojern
  * By visiting <https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/?affiliateId=111>, checking the opt-out box and clicking ‘Submit Opt-outs’; or 
  * Through the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising, of which Sojern is a member. This programme provides an opt-out page where you can exercise control over members/’participants’ cookies from a central location.

To opt-out of NAI members’ or DAA participants’ cookies, visit: 
  * NAI: <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>
  * DAA: <https://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

#### Types of cookies used 

The table below sets out the cookies used on flyscoot.com and explains their use: 

**Cookies used on[www.flyscoot.com](https://www.flyscoot.com/en/) and [makeabooking.flyscoot.com](https://makeabooking.flyscoot.com/)**

Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
UniqueReportID| Used to identify multi tabbing during the booking process.   
HandShake| Used to share Scoot Insider details between DotRez and CorpSite.  
RetainedContactInfodotRez| Used for the “retain contact information” check box in DotRez’s payment page.   
tzmememberportal| This cookie is used to retain login information in member’s portal  
sf-trckngckie| Logs the page visit.  
sf-tracking-consent| Saves the tracking consent choice, made by visitors.   
sf-site| In multisite environment, remembers the ID of the current site.   
ASP.NET_SessionId| Contains information about the browser session and enables visitors to log into the website.   
.ASPXAUTH| Determines whether a user is authenticated.   
.SFAUTH| Used for authentication tickets caching.   
.SFROLES| Used to cache user roles.   
.SFLOG| Used to pass the reason to login form and to display the reason.   
.AspNet.Cookies| The relying party cookie that is used to cache authentication information.   
.AspNet.Temp.Cookies| Helper relying party cookie during authentication.  
SF-TokenId| Handles the claims token (claims authentication mode).   
sf_timezoneoffset| Stores the value of the UTC time zone offset for the particular user, that is, the timezone difference between UTC and the user's local time, in minutes. This cookie is stored only for logged in users.   
selectedDisplayCurrency| Holds the display currency selected by the customer.   
VisitorsCounterUniqueId| Used for counting web visits as a unique parameter.   
cartOrderId| Used to cache current cart order ID - only if configured.   
idsrv| IdentityServer3 cookie used to cache information about the current user. Expiration depends on Remember me checkbox. Configuration in AuthenticationConfig.  
OpenIdConnect.nonce| Used to validate the identity token received from the Identity Provider (IdenityServer). It is a session cookie, but the information contained expires in 1 hour  
sf_abtest| Used for A/B testing, this cookie stores the IDs of the page variations   
loc| Tracks the current user's current country. This is automatically set depending on user’s geolocation  
curr| Keep tracks users default currency based on user’s current country  
  
#### 3\. Clickstream data

In order to improve your online experience, Scoot may track online behaviour or clickstream data to advance your use of our Website and track referrals from other websites. Such data will not be stored to your customer record, and will only be aggregated for statistical analysis.
